Preliminary Inventory of the Diane Ravitch Papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Audio Cassettes, 1989-2003 and undated (Folder 57)
  - Thomas Sobol's task force (original), New York City, 1989 November 22 (Folder 57)
  - Multicultural education, 1990 February 22 (Folder 57)
  - Supercomm '92, general session, Chicago, 1992 June 15-18 (Folder 57)
  - "What Is Found There,", 1993 (Folder 57)
  - Talk of the Nation: National Education Standards, 1993 (Folder 57)
  - Jean Feraca Show, 1995 February 28 (Box 57)
  - ROTP during weekly radio address, Roosevelt Room, White House, Washington, D.C., 1997 November 21 (Box 57)
  - EX720 -Diane Ravitch, 2000 September 6 (Box 57)
  - Vox POP, 2000 September 13 (Box 57)
  - Harang, Joan, 2000 September 15 (Box 57)
  - Diane Ravitch - Education, Diane Rehm, 2000 September 29 (Box 57)
  - Left Back: A Century of Failed School Reform. (Box 57)
    3 audio cassettes
    - January series, Calvin College, 2001 January 16 (Box 57)
    - Part I, 2001 April 10 (Box 57)
    - Part 2, 2001 April 16 (Box 57)
  - (?) "Frosh Sil" tape from Michelle, 2003 May 12 (Box 57)
  - Walden's Pond, 2003 August 3 (Box 57)
- CD Rom, 2000-2007 (Box 58)
  - The Merro report - Lively conversations about youth and learning from National Public Radio, 2000-2001 (Box 58)
    2 CD Rom
  - New York City Schools - Mayor Michael Bloomberg's articles from New York press, 2002 (Box 58)
  - CATO Audio - CATO Institute, 2004 (Box 58)
  - Diane Ravitch - "Pathways of Learning,", 2007 September 17 (Box 58)
    See also Carol Gresser Forem - Photographs, 2007 March 27
- Writings on diskettes, 1980-1993 (Box 58, Reading room workstation)
  - Untitled manuscript chapters, modified 1-3 January 1980, 22 January 1992 (Box 58, Reading room workstation)
    Chap 1, "The Good Old Days"; Chap 2, Noah Webster and His Speller; Chap 3, Early Textbooks; Chap 4, History Enters the Schools; Chap 5, Reforms and Reformers; Chap 6, The Era of McGuffey; Chap 7, Worthy Knowledge; Chap 8, The Committee of Ten; Library, a list of references (two 5.25-inch disks, unlabelled). Use copies available at reading room workstation
  - "Standards in American Educational History,", modified 20 September 1993 (Box 58, Reading room workstation)
    (one 3.5-inch disk with label: Vinovskis, Maris A.) Use copies available at reading room workstation
- Photographs and slides, 1956-1988 and undated (Box 58)
  See also CD Rom
  - 1 photographic print depicting Diane Ravitch, undated (Box 58)
  - 4 color slides and related materials, undated (Box 58)
  - 2 photographic prints depicting Diane Ravitch and other unidentified individuals, undated (Box 58)
  - 8 photographic prints depicting Diane Ravitch and other unidentified individuals assembled in different cities at different times participating in events to commemorate the Solidarity movement of 1956-1980, undated (Box 58)
  - 1 photographic print depicting two young boys, Joshua (8 years old) and Trevor (4/1-2) years old, 1988 October 19 (Box 58)
  - 1 photographic print depicting Fengshi Yang, Washington, D.C., 1989 (Box 58)
  - Carol Gresser Forem - Photographs, 2007 March 27 (Box 58)
- VHS Videocassettes, 1991-2005 and undated (Box 58)
  - Herman Badillo's Education Forum - Guest: Diane Ravitch, undated (Box 58)
  - School: The Story of American Public Education (Box 58)
    - Episode 1, "The Common School (1770-1890),", undated (Box 58)
    - Episode 2, "As American as Public School (1900-1950),", undated (Box 58)
    - Episode 3, "Equality (1950-1980),", undated (Box 58)
    - Episode 4, "The Bottom Line (1980-Present), undated (Box 58)
  - "Improving History," Department of Education, Al Shanker, 1991 (Box 58)
    Questions and answers
  - Educational Panel, Golden Circle, Day 2/Session 4, 1994 (Box 58)
  - "Reinventing Public School, episode 4, fine cut with titles, 1999 April 12 (Box 58)
  - Baruch College School of Public Affairs - "New York City's Public Schools Confront a New Year," parts 1 and 2, 2004 September 28 (Box 58)
  - Brown Center Event, 2005 June 1 (Box 58)
- Diane Ravitch (Box 59)
  - On history, 1984-1989 (Box-folder 59: 1)
    Includes articles, clippings, and printed matter
  - On tests, 1989 (Box-folder 59: 2)
  - Outcome Based Education (OBE), 1991-1995 (Box-folder 59: 3)
    Article, clipping, report, and related materials
  - Political Pork, 1992-1995 (Box-folder 59: 4)
  - Cremin, Lawrence A., 1987 (Box-folder 59: 5)
  - Tot, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 59: 6)
  - Wall Street Journal, 1990 (Box-folder 59: 7)
  - Schlesinger, Arthur Jr., 1990 (Box-folder 59: 8)
  - Reaction to Ravitch on multiculturalism, 1990 (Box-folder 59: 9)
  - California curriculum packet, 1987-1990 (Box-folder 59: 10)
    Article, clipping, and remarks
  - Cultural literacy, 1987 (Box-folder 59: 11)
  - Curriculum of Inclusion, 1989-1990 (Box-folder 59: 12-13)
    Agenda of a meeting and notes
  - Curriculum of Truth, undated (Box-folder 59: 14)
  - Daily News, 1990 (Box-folder 59: 15-16)
  - "Diversity and Democracy," American Educator, 1990 (Box-folder 60: 1)
    Article
  - Democracy, undated (Box-folder 60: 2)
  - The Educational Excellence Network (EEN), 1989 (Box-folder 60: 3)
    Report. Includes an article by Diane Ravitch
- Writings by others, 1989 and undated (Box-folder 60: 4)
  Includes articles, flyers, remarks, and review
- Miscellany, 1984-1997 and undated (Box-folder 60: 5)
- Incremental Materials (Box 61-65)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.